Joseph Moore

Software Engineer

Objective

Innovative programmer looking for opportunity on a collaborative team that prioritizes sustainable innovation and software craftsmanship. With 13 years experience, I am looking for the freedom to solve real problems in an open, honest forum with a healthy work/life balance.

Accomplishments & Notable Projects

- Lead a full-stack team building a new account creation process that showed a 50% improvement in sign up conversions.
- Rapidly delivered an enterprise-wide integration with a new, API-driven payment solution.
- Guided transition from a monolithic, Java/Spring stack to a simpler, Kotlin-based microservice model.
- Pioneered the BYU Web Brand framework and a git-based CDN that allowed for fast pageloads and timely updates and bugfixes (btc.thatjoemoore.com and cdn.thatjoemoore.com).
- Received two BYU Staff and Administrative Employee Recognition Award and a Nu Skin Pinnacle award.

Professional Experience

Senior Software Engineer, Nu Skin Enterprises

October 2019 - Present

- Lead a cross-functional team building applications in Vue.js and Node.js.
- Championed Continuous Deployment and automated testing practices.
- Lead collaboration between UX design, product ownership, engineering, and stakeholders to craft solutions for user problems.

Software Developer, Brigham Young University Office of IT

May 2012 - October 2019

- Lead small project teams in design, development, and maintenance of full-stack, event- and API-driven applications in Java, Kotlin, Node.js, and Vue.js.
- Collaborated with campus community to design and implement a crossframework web brand.
- Advocated best practices as part of cross-functional working groups.
- Architected and crafted shared infrastructure and deployment tooling.
- Mentored junior developers and student developers in all aspects of software development.

Student Developer, Brigham Young University Office of IT

August 2008 - May 2012

- Overhauled the BYU Android App, taking it from a quick minimum viable product to a feature-rich, maintainable application.
- Developed UIs for Web (Java, Spring) and Desktop (Java Swing).
- Build backend web APIs in Java (Spring, Hibernate) using SOAP and RESTful styles.

& Removed

github.com/ThatJoeMoore

dev.to/ThatJoeMoore

Top Skills

Backend Development

Node.js, Java, Kotlin, Scala, Go

Web Development

Vue.js, Svelte, HTML, Javascript, CSS, Web Components, JSP/Servlet

API Development

REST, SOAP, JSON, XML, OpenAPI/Swagger

Automated Testing

Jest, JUnit, Mocha, Artillery, Selenium, Puppeteer

Architectures

Microservices, Asynchronous Events, Web APIs

Data Persistence

SQL, Hibernate, JDBC, DynamoDB, Google Cloud Datastore, S3

Infrastructure

AWS, GCP, Serverless, Linux, Docker, Infrastructure As Code

Engineering Practices

Agile, CI/CD, Test-Driven Development, Domain-Driven Design

Security & Compliance

PCI-DSS, FERPA, HIPAA, Web Application Security

Education & Certifications

Brigham Young University

2005-2006 & 2008-2012

Completed 96 credit hours toward BS in Mechanical Engineering

AWS Certified Solutions Architect

Associate Level